TOMMY REDDAD

Montréal, Québec, Canada · ♥

reddad.ca · • tommy.reddad@gmail.com ·
github.com/tommyreddad · • linkedin.com/in/tommy-reddad · linkedin.com/in/t

Profile

Python and JavaScript developer and computer scientist with 5 years of experience in academic research, specializing in applied probability theory, statistics, machine learning, and the analysis of algorithms. Deep learning enthusiast with particular interest in natural language processing.

Key Competences

Coding

Python (numpy, matplotlib, TensorFlow, PyTorch, pandas), JavaScript (TypeScript, D3.js, React.js), C(++), R, Java, SQL, OpenGL, HTML, CSS, git, Visual Studio Code, Emacs, LATeX, *nix.

Data Science

Strong understanding of the fundamentals of machine learning and deep learning, including popular techniques, e.g., regression, PCA, SVMs, neural networks, SGD, backpropagation, CNNs, RNNs, GANs, (variational) autoencoders, transformers. Good knowledge of contemporary techniques in NLU.

Research and Leadership

Experienced in conducting advanced academic research in computer science and mathematics, both independently and through managing group projects. Ability to communicate and coordinate effectively with mathematicians and programmers alike. Skilled in algorithm development. Experienced with agile development.

Education

PhD candidate, Computer Science (incomplete)	2016—2019
McGill University, Montréal, Canada	GPA: $4.00/4.00$
Master of Computer Science	2013—2015
Carleton University, Ottawa, Canada	GPA: 11.8/12.0
Master's thesis: Encoding Arguments	
BSc, Joint Honours in Mathematics and Computer Science	2010—2013
McGill University	GPA: $3.92/4.00$

Professional Experience

NLU Research Intern

Cerence Inc. at MILA 2019—2020

- Implemented state-of-the-art optimizers and deep learning algorithms efficiently in TensorFlow.
- Researched methods to improve the performance and training time of deep neural networks for the purpose of natural language understanding.

Software Developer Intern

Cerence Inc. 2019

- Contributed to agile development of a large TypeScript/C++ application for speech processing on automotive embedded systems.
- Developed from scratch a new plugin for TypeDoc, a TypeScript documentation engine, with enhanced features including tag validation, color-coding by tag, and improved link validation.

McGill University 2016—2019

• Studied various problems in minimax density estimation (1 peer-reviewed journal article, 2 other papers), and the detection of the spread of an infection in a random network (1 peer-reviewed journal article). Many other unpublished works especially concerning random trees.

Awarded the Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada's Postgraduate Doctoral Scholarship through 2017—2019.

Teaching Assistant

McGill University

Carleton University

2016—2019
2013—2015

Held weekly office hours for diverse undergraduate and graduate level university courses in computer science, with responsibilities including grading, designing homework questions, and lecturing.

Research Assistant

Carleton University 2013—2015 McGill University 2012, 2013

• Studied encoding arguments as a proof technique (1 peer-reviewed journal article, Master's thesis), the Shannon capacity of graphs, and the geometric analysis of maps and balance in competitive multiplayer video games (1 paper). Many other unpublished works concerning random trees and computational geometry.

Publications

- [1] L. Devroye, A. Mehrabian, and T. Reddad. The minimax learning rate of normal and Ising undirected graphical models. *arXiv e-prints*, abs/1806.06887, 2018.
- [2] L. Devroye, A. Mehrabian, and T. Reddad. The total variation distance between high-dimensional Gaussians. arXiv e-prints, abs/1810.08693, 2018.
- [3] L. Devroye and T. Reddad. On the discovery of the seed in uniform attachment trees. *Internet Mathematics*, 2019.
- [4] L. Devroye and T. Reddad. Discrete minimax estimation with trees. *Electron. J. Stat.*, 13(2):2595–2623, 2019.
- [5] P. Morin, W. Mulzer, and T. Reddad. Encoding arguments. *ACM Computing Surveys*, 50(3):1–46, 2017.
- [6] T. Reddad. Encoding arguments. Master's thesis, Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada, 2015.
- [7] T. Reddad and C. Verbrugge. Geometric analysis of maps in real-time strategy games: Measuring map quality in a competitive setting. Technical Report GR@M-TR-2012-3, McGill University, GR@M, Games Research At McGill, School of Computer Science, 2012.